ulm.edu 2018-08-09

# Statements & Policies | ULM University of Louisiana at Monroe

**Commitment To Privacy**

University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM) University (University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM) or “University”) is committed to maintaining the privacy and security of any collected confidential or highly sensitive personal information. This policy has been adopted to address the collection, use, and dissemination of personal information by the University. This policy is subject to change over time, as the technologies utilized to provide services via the Internet continue to develop and evolve. Despite changes in technology, any alterations to this policy will not affect the University’s commitment to privacy. 

**General Statement**

This policy applies to all information digitally collected by or submitted to University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM). University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM) receives information via two primary methods: 

  * Information collected automatically via websites
  * Information voluntarily provided by the user in order to receive information and/or services (via web forms and email). 

**Information Collection**

**3.1 Automatic Collection**

If a user has not taken specific steps to anonymize their personal web traffic (e.g. apply mechanisms such as the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on that disable the collection of data for analytical purposes), official University websites may collect certain information automatically. This information includes, but is not limited to: 

  * User’s Internet protocol (IP) address
  * Internet service provider
  * Operating system
  * The time and date of the visit
  * Browser
  * The site from which the user visited
  * Cookie information (if applicable)

Any information collected automatically is not associated with any other information held by University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM) (i.e. not linked with information voluntarily provided to University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM)) unless University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM) is required to do so by law. 

**3.2 Voluntary Submission**

In order to provide information and/or services, University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM) may request users to provide personal data, some of which may be personally identifiable information. Information such as name, date of birth, email address, etc. can be collected via voluntary submission of an email or web form to a University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM) entity. 

**Information Use**

Website information that is gathered automatically is utilized to improve the understanding of how University-provided websites are being leveraged by the user community. For example, some University websites use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. Google Analytics uses “cookies” (i.e. files used to track website activity) to determine how users navigate University sites. Google uses this cookie data for various purposes, including the evaluation of website use, reports on website activity, and other services. Please visit the following pages for more information on Google Analytics’ terms of use and Google’s privacy practices. 

Any information submitted to University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM) voluntarily in order to receive services and/or information will only be utilized to conduct official university business. University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM) may disseminate voluntarily submitted information to third parties and offices/departments within the University to the extent necessary in order to provide the requested services and/or information. University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM) may also disseminate such information if required by applicable international, federal, state and/or local laws. 

University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM) will not disclose any information submitted voluntarily for reasons other than mentioned above, without clear notice and the opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such uses. University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM) will never sell or trade voluntarily submitted information to other entities unless a prior consent has been obtained and/or such information is being shared in response to a subpoena, court order, or legal process. 

There is no legal requirement for a user to provide any information to the University. However, without certain information, University websites and services may not function as intended and features may be inaccessible. 

**Use Of Cookies**

Some University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM) websites use cookies (beyond cookies utilized by Google Analytics), which enable University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM) to further tailor its web services to the needs of the user community. Cookie data assists the University in improving both web content and distribution. Users have the right to refuse the use of cookies by implementing technical configurations in their web browsers; however, functionalities of certain sites may be impacted if such configurations are implemented. 

**External Links**

Some University sites may contain links to external websites not owned by, or officially affiliated with, University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM) in any way. If a user decides to navigate to external links, he/she will leave the University website and thus, the University is not responsible for privacy practices or the content of such websites. Navigating to external links is done at the user’s own risk and users should be aware that University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM)’s policies no longer apply. University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM) recommends that users review the privacy policy and applicable terms of all sites they visit. 

**Data Security**

In addition to complying with all applicable laws and regulations, the University strives to implement and maintain systems and policies to protect the confidentiality and integrity of personal information provided by users. Despite these security measures, the University does not represent or warrant that personal information will be protected against loss, misuse or alteration by third parties.  Any information transmitted to University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM) by the user is done so at the user’s own risk. Once the information is received by University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM), the University will make every effort to ensure the security of data on University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM)’s systems. 

**GDPR Notice**

The purpose of the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) is to protect all European Union (“EU”) citizens from privacy and data breaches by allowing citizens to maintain control of the personal data kept and processed by organizations. The GDPR also protects the personal data of individuals, regardless of citizenry, in the EU. 

University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM) University is committed to safeguarding the privacy of personal data. This GDPR Notice outlines the collection, use, and disclosure of personal information provided to the University by students, faculty and staff, alumni and other members of our community to which the GDPR applies. When information is submitted to University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM) University, or you use the University’s websites and other services, you consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of that information as described in this GDPR Notice. 

**8.1 University Use of Information**

University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM) University collects and processes personal data (“Information”) from individuals only as necessary in the exercise of the University’s legitimate interests, functions and responsibilities as a public institution of higher education. For example, University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM) University also collects and processes Information from individuals who are applicants for employment positions. Information collected from students or student applicants is used to register or enroll persons in the University, provide and administer housing to students, manage a student account, provide academic advising, develop and deliver education programs, track academic progress, analyze and improve education programs, recruitment, regulatory reporting, auditing, maintenance of accreditation, and other related University processes and functions. University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM) University also uses Information to conduct general demographic and statistical research to improve University programs, to identify appropriate support services or activities, provide reasonable accommodations, enforce University policies or comply with applicable laws. Finally, Information may be shared by University of Louisiana Monroe (ULM) University with third parties who have entered into contracts with the University to perform functions on behalf of the University, subject to the obligation of confidentiality and safeguarding from unauthorized disclosure. 

**8.2 Third Party Use of Sensitive Information**

We may disclose your Sensitive Information and other Information as follows:

  * Consent: We may disclose Information if we have your consent to do so.
  * Emergency Circumstances: We may share your Information when necessary to protect your interests and you are physically or legally incapable of providing consent. 
  * Employment Necessity: We may share your Information when necessary for administering employment or social security benefits in accordance with applicable law or any applicable collective bargaining agreement, subject to the imposition of appropriate safeguards to prevent further unauthorized disclosure. 
  * Public Information: We may share your Information if you have manifestly made it public.
  * Archiving: We may share your Information for archival purposes in the public interest, and for historical research and statistical purposes. 
  * Performance of a Contract: We may share your Information when necessary to administer a contract you have with the University. 
  * Legal Obligation: We may share your Information when the disclosure is required or permitted by international, federal, and state laws and regulations. 
  * Service Providers: We use third parties who have entered into a contract with the University to support the administration of University operations and policies. In such cases, we share your Information with such third parties subject to the imposition of appropriate safeguards to prevent further unauthorized disclosure. 
  * University-Affiliated Programs: We may share your Information with parties that are affiliated with the University for the purpose of contacting you about goods, services, charitable giving or experiences that may be of interest to you. 
  * De-Identified and Aggregate Information: We may use and disclose Information in de-identified or aggregate form without limitation. 

**8.3 Security**

We implement appropriate technical and organizational security measures to protect your information when you transmit it to us and when we store it on our information technology systems. 

**8.4 Retention and Destruction of Your Information**

Your information will be retained by the University in accordance with applicable state and federal laws, and the University’s applicable retention periods. Your information will be destroyed upon your request unless applicable law requires destruction after the expiration of an applicable retention period (See Policy 1306 – Records Retention and Disposition). The manner of destruction shall be appropriate to preserve and ensure the confidentiality of your information given the level of sensitivity, value and criticality to the University. 

**8.5 Your Rights**

Through the GDPR, You have the right to request access to, a copy of, rectification, restriction in the use of, or erasure of your information in accordance with all applicable laws. The erasure of your information shall be subject to applicable state and federal laws, and the applicable retention period. If you have provided consent to the use of your information, you have the right to withdraw consent without affecting the lawfulness of the University’s use of the information prior to receipt of your request. 

Information created in the European Union will be transferred out of the European Union to the University. If you feel the University has not complied with applicable foreign laws regulating such information, you have the right to file a complaint with the appropriate supervisory authority in the European Union. 

**Contact Information**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement or if you would like to report an issue or complaint, please contact the University at [taylor@ulm.edu](mailto:taylor@ulm.edu?subject=privacy%20notice).
